<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Your go-to hub for professional insights with a playful twist!</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Your go-to hub for professional insights with a playful twist!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 08:50:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>100 Questions to Test Your Knowledge of AWS AI Cloud Services</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/quizonawsaiservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 08:50:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/quizonawsaiservices/</guid>
      <description>100 Questions to Test Your Knowledge of AWS AI Cloud Services&#xA;Define these terms:&#xA;Amazon Bedrock Amazon Titan Agents for Amazon Bedrock Third party Bedrock models Amazon Sagemaker Jumpstart Public models Proprietary models Managed Infrastructure Sagemaker model training Sagemaker model deployment Amazon OpenSearch (k-NN plugin) Amazon Kendra Amazon Aurora/RDS for postgresSQL (pgvector) AWS Trainium AWS Inferentia Amazon CodeWhisperer AWs HealthScribe Generative Bi in Amazon QuickSight When should you use:&#xA;Copy list above Why use Bedrock</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Presentation about AWS AI Services</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/aws-ai-services-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 08:50:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/aws-ai-services-presentation/</guid>
      <description>Leveraging AWS Cloud for AI&#xA;Situation You have an orderly and stable IT infrastructure Complication You want to use AI Setting up AI is hard and expensive slides hsowing the costs of AI models Slide showing skills shortages You don&amp;rsquo;t have time, skills and expertise to build your own in-house solution You want some flexibility and choice in the tools and platforms you use You think that if you don&amp;rsquo;t get going now, you will never catch up Resolution Leverage AWS Bedrock and AWS Sagemaker </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI and Your Career</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/aiandyourcareer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 08:50:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/aiandyourcareer/</guid>
      <description>Of course AI is the hosttest thing in tech now, so should you go all in or should you be wary?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Being Negative In the Workplace</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/beingnegativeintheworkplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 08:50:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/beingnegativeintheworkplace/</guid>
      <description>Being Negative In the Workplace Oh boy, its really hard to be negative in the workplace, especailly when you are surrounded by a bunch of pollyanna types that are always looking for the positive in everything or who are afraid of any accountability.&#xA;What should yyou do if you find yourself in that situation.&#xA;The best solution is to leave. If you can&amp;rsquo;t leave, then you need to find a way to be positive in the workplace.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices In Architecting Cloud Applications in AWS Cloud</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bestpracticesinarchitectingaws/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 08:50:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bestpracticesinarchitectingaws/</guid>
      <description>Best Practices In Architecting Cloud Applications in AWS Cloud Sources: https://learning.oreilly.com/library/view/cloud-computing-principles/9780470887998/ch18.html?_ga=2.188552232.1250616195.1709644639-1298335628.1693925591&amp;amp;_gac=1.159689295.1708006412.CjwKCAiAibeuBhAAEiwAiXBoJO0yon0yh8hj74v82NIvrN_5eF2Z-dkQpbBLtHNGLc3XIp9uMJe0hRoCASEQAvD_BwE</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bits and Blueprint</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bitsandblueprints/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 08:50:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bitsandblueprints/</guid>
      <description>Bits and Blueprints Bits and Blueprints is my informal blog, where I write down and explore ideas. Its a collection of semi-finished &amp;rsquo;notes&amp;rsquo; on techncial topics of interest to me. I find that writing things is the best way to educate and understand any topic.&#xA;This blog will have some very techncial content that you might find in a design blueprint.&#xA;My areas of interest include:&#xA;AI System Design Solution Architecture IT Strategy IT Governance Cloud Enterprise Architecture Product Analysis Some of this content will be edited and posted to my substack, medium and linkedin accounts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Business Benefits of Cloud Computing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/businessbenefitsofcloudcomputing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 08:50:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/businessbenefitsofcloudcomputing/</guid>
      <description>Business Benefits of Cloud Computing Just in time infrastructure Little Upfront Infrastructure Investment More Efficient Resource Utilization Usage Based Costing Reduced Time to Market </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Quality Will Be King in an AI World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dataqualitywillbeking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 08:50:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dataqualitywillbeking/</guid>
      <description>Data Quality Will be King in an AI World </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Cloud Based AI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gettingstartedincloudbasedai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 08:50:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gettingstartedincloudbasedai/</guid>
      <description>Getting Started with Cloud Based AI T</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to use McKinsey SCR framework</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/howtousescrframework/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 08:50:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/howtousescrframework/</guid>
      <description>The Situation-Complication-Resolution (SCR) Framework provides a structure for clearly defining business challenges and outlining strategies and solutions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Worst Mistakes In The Cloud</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/myworstmistakesinthecloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 08:50:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/myworstmistakesinthecloud/</guid>
      <description>Cloud Mistakes Here they are:&#xA;Running systems doing nothing Lift and Shift Naive Use of Cloud Storage Poor Planning Weak Governance No Strategy Shiny Object Syndrome Lack of Automation Lack of Monitoring Lack of Testing Lack of Security Lack of Backups Lack of Disaster Recovery Lack of Change Management Lack of Incident Response Lack of Incident Reporting Lack of Incident Review Lack of Incident Lessons Learned Lack of Incident Closure Lack of Incident Root Cause Analysis Lack of Incident Post Mortem Lack of Incident Retrospective Lack of Incident Action Items Lack of Incident Escalation </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RAG Chronicles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rag/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 08:50:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rag/</guid>
      <description>RAG Chronicles 1 This is article 1 about building a RAG application.&#xA;Understand the Domain Understand the Customer Choose your tools and platforms Manage your data sources Manage your data pipleine Design your system Build, test and deploy User Experience Monitoring and Feedback Understand the Domain Every human domain has its own special language and terminology&#xA;Figure out how to handle content Understand the Customer Choose your tools and platforms There are already a number of tools out there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ten Reasons To Regret Cloud Adoption</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/reasonstoavoidthecloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 08:50:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/reasonstoavoidthecloud/</guid>
      <description>Plan:&#xA;ten specific reasons people have regretted going to the cloud Causes of why this happened How to avoid this Ten Reasons People Have Regretted Going to the Cloud Total costs did not actually go down Minimal savings on existing on-premise data centers and workloads Existing staff did not actually increase capacity and workload No noticeable improvement in service levels (availability, latency, etc) No increase in speed to market or value No noticeable improvement in security Causes:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Storage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cloudstorage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 08:50:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cloudstorage/</guid>
      <description>Cloud Storage When deciding if , when and how to store your data, it is important to understand the different cloud storage options available.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corporate IT is a Kitchen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/itkitchen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 08:50:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/itkitchen/</guid>
      <description>Corporate IT is Like a Home Kitchen Internal IT departments are like the home cook that prepares the meals for the family.&#xA;What you will find:&#xA;Everyone will complain about your cooking and the meals you make. A few thank yous is all you can expect Everyone will want their own special meals. One person will want vegetarian only, and another will demand more meat. Evertone will ask for more spicy or less spicy.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
